Mom.
The wreath fell again.
Okay. I thought
I saw something.
Okay.
What are you reading?
Green Lantern.
It's Earth's branch of the
intergalactic police force.
Makes things
happen with his mind.
Well, his ring.
But it's mostly his mind.
Yeah.
Maybe they
should write a comic
about a middle-aged
Louisville nurse
whose pheromones cause
men to lose their minds.
I'd read that.
What? Humor me.
The level to which I humor
you is already off the charts.
Please just eat your toast.
All right, we
should take your temp.
This isn't a cartoon.
My temperature doesn't
go up when I get mad.
You're mad?
I can't,
can't keep this up.
I know it's hard.
We both just have to be
strong just until it breaks.
Me or the blizzard?
You behave out there.
So'd you ever start your
graphic novel thingy?
Well, I sat down to draw it
and I was like, "Oh shit,
I should probably come
up with a story first."
A grand opening, grand closing.
Well, I'm sure
you have some ideas.
I wanna write something dark.
Something karmic, but
engaging and hopeful, too.
I, I don't know.
Well, I could help.
Hey!
I'll autograph one for
you when I'm done, okay?
Just gimme some space.
Okay.
There is something you
could do that might help.
Tell me the worst
thing you've ever done.
Well, that's a bit direct.
Before you had me.
I don't,
I don't wanna tell you.
Wouldn't be that
useful if you did.
Well...
the people and the
places are a b-, a blur,
but I remember
I was a bad person.
You? Or the drugs?
I'm glad that you can
make the distinction
between the two,
but no, it was me.
I, I enjoyed
corrupting innocence,
mm, you know, giving them
a taste of the darkness
that flowed through my veins.
It was, it was worse than
misery loving company.
It was, it was chaos
making chaos for breakfast.
Mm.
20 years ago, right?
Ancient history.
Mm. No, you don't just
click your heels and run...
Have a pass waiting for
you like that in the dark.
Or outside the window.
Mm, chaos making
chaos for breakfast.
The past is a bitch like that.
At least you
didn't kill anybody.
Not like you're
gonna kill me.
That is not the most accurate.
My asshole's frozen shut.
I think I stacked
the dishes funny.
Dry off. I'll be right back.
Look at all the decorations.
They have decorations. I
hope there's no kids here.
What?
Well, I don't
wanna freak them out.
I don't wanna freak anybody out!
Come here.
Kory?
-Yeah?
-This doesn't feel right.
No, Lizzie,
it feels warm.
Look, we need to go!
Where?
Run!
Get out of my house!
What the?
-Stop! Stop!
-Wait! Wait!
Okay, wait? Just
wait a second, okay?
We're not here to hurt anybody.
We, we just wanted
to get out of the cold.
Bullshit!
I'm sorry, okay?
This was a mistake.
-Yeah!
-Yeah, I told you that
10 fucking minutes ago.
I need a doctor. Hey, lady,
are you a nurse or something?
No, and you need to get
the hell out of here now.
But ma'am, it
is freezing outside.
I can't walk.
I'm fucking dying.
You're not dying.
You have to help me.
That's a rule, isn't it, right?
It's like the, the, uh, what
is it, the Hippocratic Oath?
-What are you-
-No, that's doctors.
Nurses take the
Nightingale Pledge.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Hey, that doesn't cover
home fucking invasion.
Okay, we can debate
that while he bleeds
all over your floor.
There'll be more damages
than we meant to cause.
Do you know what'll happen
if you send us out there?
I'm not sure I'd be able
to live with myself.
But your house, your call.
Please, please.
Dammit. Help me
get him to the couch.
-Breathe, just breathe.
-Okay.
-I'm breathing!
-Little faster.
I think I'm hyperventilating.
I'm gonna fucking pass out now.
-Ow, fuck, come on!
-Ooh, sorry,
-sorry, sorry!
-Ow! Oh, fuck.
Ooh, okay, rags.
-Huh?
-In the kitchen
underneath the sink!
Ah, okay, I'm ready.
Just, just, just yank it.
Yeah, it's not
gonna be that simple.
What?
What is that?
No, no, no, no, no
tools, no, no. It's okay.
Trust me, this is the easy way.
Uh, what do I do?
Roll it up and
put it in his mouth.
Okay.
Hell of a time to
be out for a stroll.
Blizzard's been full tilt
for the past six days.
Yeah, I told her that this
little missionary trip
could wait till spring.
-This isn't-
-Well 'tis the season.
All right.
Hold the bat still.
There's gonna be
more blood coming.
Here we go.
All right.
Oh, shit! Sorry!
What the fuck, man?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. Are you ready
No!
-Okay.
-Just you here?
I have a daughter.
She has a fever.
Is that her room at the door?
She's not a basket
case or something?
Apply pressure.
Do not leave this room.
Charm?
Charm.
You hammer,
I'll see to his knee,
and we'll figure
out the rest later.
Nice house. Must be
one heck of a nurse.
I had a hospice patient.
We worked together
for two years.
I didn't think she
liked me very much,
but she went, her will came,
it was hers, and now it's mine.
Thanks.
Guest room.
It's yours for the night.
Does that make you feel safe?
Yeah, absolutely. What
makes you feel safe?
Big bats with screws in them.
So what's your daughter's deal?
I told you. She has a fever.
Yeah, it must be pretty bad.
And all the metal.
She's prone to
psychotic episodes.
I'd insist that you stay away.
You're the boss, Nightingale.
Yeah.
Thanks again.
I heard voices.
Are there really
people down there?
Uh, yeah, they just,
they got caught in the storm,
so it's just gonna
be for a few hours.
I could get dressed, say hi.
You know that's not a good idea.
I just, I just wanna
talk to somebody.
Charm, these people, they're,
they're drifters, okay?
The 8 ball they did in
the shelter's probably
the only reason why
they're not frozen solid.
You would know.
I would fucking know!
Can you just trust
me for once? Please?
2.4 degrees.
That's all that's keeping her
from slipping away from me.
Again.
I know addiction,
I know sickness,
but what has Charm is
a biological nightmare,
and I'm fighting it the
only way that I know how,
but that, that safe
zone, that coveted window
is getting harder and
harder to maintain.
I'm so tired and my
sweet, sweet girl, she is
running out of time.
We got lucky.
Wasn't luck.
Yeah, no, I know it.
I'm just, you know what I mean.
You mean we found the house
at the end of the rainbow
like the leprechaun
said we would?
Oh, look under the cushion.
Maybe there's some gold coins
sprinkled about, laddie.
I get it already.
And credit where it's due, huh?
No, just saying
that this is an extremely
fortunate situation.
Found a nice warm
house with the power on
and the hostess is a nurse among
other bucket-list fetishes.
That was a joke, Liz.
But I
tell you that anyone
who looks at a woman lustfully
has already committed adultery
with her in his heart.
Liz, I'm not married.
I'm sorry. I'm in your
corner no matter what.
We just can't have
another misunderstanding.
Okay.
Not now.
So what are you
looking for exactly?
Intracranial hemorrhaging.
It's a possible side effect
from a prolonged fever.
So brain damage.
It's just a precaution.
Heavy recovery from any
medication has a mini withdrawal
Psychosis is a possibility.
Auditory and visual
hallucinations,
lucid sleepwalking,
but you'll be fine.
When you said you made mistakes
before, was I one of them?
I've made mistakes before you,
after you, with you,
but never you.
So who are they downstairs?
Um, they're just some kids
who got caught in the storm.
Kids?
Well, no, no, they're adults.
Well, you just said kids.
Okay, it's a figure of speech.
Which is the exact
opposite of adults.
Why are you pushing me?
I'm not pushing you.
I just wanna have some
normal interaction with-
Well, you're not normal!
You're more, Charm.
You're more, okay?
You're more than anyone
could ever understand.
And what's happening right now
leads away from logic
into pure phenomena,
so it, it, it
doesn't make it easier.
It makes it harder.
I promise I won't
give up if you don't,
but you have to trust me.
All right. Maybe a quick dinner.
What are those? Those aren't
what you normally, um...
Dinner or not, kiddo?
Okay. Well, I will
leave the door unlocked.
Come down in about 20 minutes.
Oh, come on man. You're
gotta say something.
She's gonna think you're
a fucking serial killer.
Um, hey, going hiking?
Who are you now?
Our little home invader?
Yeah. Yep, that's me, Kory.
Sorry, um, uh, it, it, it, just,
I'm not, I'm not
dangerous, okay.
Said every serial killer ever.
Okay, please, please
don't. Please don't scream.
Liz will freak out and then-
Liz?
Yeah, that's my sister who
thinks she is my mother.
You know, I love her,
I, I, it's just like,
don't you wish people would
back the fuck off sometimes?
All the time.
You coming out or what?
Uh, I was sort of
thinking I'd stay here
because, uh,
if you don't see me,
then we got a little bit of,
uh, uh, plausible deniability,
you know what I mean?
So you're pretty
into porcupines, huh?
I hate them.
Oh, yeah, sure.
That explains the shrine.
It's hard to exert
control over something
when you're too
busy running from it.
Sounds like you got
some adult concerns.
Yeah, I'm
juggling a few others.
Oh, yeah. Like what?
Like the effect antifreeze
has on one's innards.
Did you know porcupine
means pig with swords?
Did you know their quills
are basically calcified hair?
I did not.
And that at the right angle
they sink into the flesh,
like hot rebar.
How did
you find that out?
The hard way.
My mom had surprised me
with a trip to the zoo.
Like always, she felt bad
and thought this would
make everything okay.
You wanna take it
outta my pocket?
-Yeah, I do!
-But even then
I could see
through her bullshit.
Where is it, huh?
What you gonna do with it?
What are you gonna do with
it? Better give it on back!
-The look in her eye.
-Who you gonna sell it to?
It was
more than hunger.
It was, it scared me,
so I ran.
There were people everywhere,
but no one helped.
Ran through the first
door I could find,
the wrong one.
Mama, Mama, Mama.
The smell hit me first.
Then I, I saw it.
Possession, negligence. They
arrested her on the spot.
How long did they keep her?
She kept herself. 7
rehab stints in 10 years.
But, but she's, uh, she's all
better now, though, right?
Like she's, uh,
rehabilitated or whatever.
Part of recovering
is letting go.
She has this old suitcase
from her party days
out in the garage.
Probably still something
in there to make
all the pain go away.
Guess all that shit with
your mom is the reason
you got the whole tortured
artist thing going on, right?
I mean, well,
I mean almost anyway, right?
What do you mean?
I don't know, I mean, um,
no obsession is complete
without a cool origin story, so.
Some battle scars might have
sold it better. That's all.
Honey
are you coming down?
Guess it's showtime.
Yeah, yeah,
I guess I better, um...
Escape?
No one's getting
out of this zoo.
What? Okay.
-Pass that.
-Oh, thank you.
Thanks.
Smells great, ma'am.
Hi, Charm. Uh, this is
Liz and that's Kory.
Uh, we appreciate
your hospitality.
We'll see.
Uh, before we start eating,
I would be honored to
lead us in a blessing.
If we could all join hands?
Heavenly Father, thank you
for leading us out of the cold
and into the limitless
warmth of Your love.
Please bless our food,
but especially our host,
hostesses who have graced us
with an all-too-rare compassion.
In Your name, we say
amen.
Let's eat.
So we're making tracks along
the road outside Shelby Bowl,
and then the snow just
starts dumping on us.
Mm-hmm, and we need shelter,
but we wanna keep moving.
-Bus, right?
-Wrong.
Some kind human
took it upon themselves
to knock down every
stop marker for like-
For like, it's
like two miles easy.
So the buses are going by us
and we're screaming
bloody murder.
Yeah, for hours, so then
I gave up and I sat down-
In the snow.
And I cried.
Yes, you did.
Mm, why didn't you just pray
for the limitless
warmth of His love?
Uh, I did that, too.
Well, help me understand.
Like, maybe you can
explain it to me.
So when you have food
right, you thank Him for it,
but when you are trapped
in sub-zero temperatures,
that's a sign, right?
A sign of what?
That God wants you
to freeze to death.
I don't think God wants
anyone to freeze to death.
I think God uses the cold
like a farmer would use
an electric fence to steer
you to where you belong.
Okay, so say God
steers you here
and I send you right back out
the window that you came in,
and then, you know,
something bad happens.
Who's the guilty party?
The party that feels guilty.
I don't know.
Doesn't His plan kind of
give me an out, though?
Like, no repercussions,
cause like, whatever I do,
whatever happens,
it's His plan, right?
Well, God...
Have you ever heard
of the term PBAB?
Pine box at bedside?
Yeah, I've been a
nurse for 10 years now,
and I've helped more
people evade death
than you could even fathom,
and it wasn't because I
waited for holy intervention
or because I
trusted in the plan.
I acted. The use of
science is an act.
And the people who believe
in the myth to save them,
they build those pine boxes
and the people who act,
we keep them empty.
I think one day
you're gonna wonder
what else you are wrong about.
Emerald twilight.
What?
Oh, Mom, you're gonna love this.
Hal Jordan, Earth's
Green Lantern, uh,
he comes back from this cosmic
ass-kicking marathon, right?
And he finds his home, Coast
City, completely annihilated.
Everything he ever loved or
held dear is just a crater.
So he's devastated
and he gets an idea.
He uses his ring to
resurrect Coast City.
All the buildings are back
and people stroll the streets,
holding hands and
sharing embraces
with the one who got away.
He even spends time
with his dead mother
till his ring runs out of power.
So he shoots up into space to
get back to his home planet
where their,
where their power source is,
and he needs it.
He needs all of it to
keep Coast City alive,
but the, the Guardians
and the other Lanterns,
they won't let him have it,
so he obliterates them all.
Charm. Charm?
No one feels guilty if
they're destroying something
in order to build.
Not God, not superheroes,
not fucking politicians.
But I think we should.
I, I think.
Charm. Charm!
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, Charm!
Oh my god, this is a
seizure. What do we do?
Can't just stand here.
We gotta do something.
Help me lie her straight.
No, you're supposed to put
something in her mouth.
What, are you a doctor now?
She's gonna fucking die, man!
Shit. The power transfer switch.
Oh great, the power transfer
switch. That's lovely.
Calm down!
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
We can't see shit and there's
a girl dying on the floor.
I apologize for losing my zen.
-Okay.
-You, you have
like a, a backup
generator or something?
No, it should have kicked on.
Flashlights?
Yes, there is a backup jenny
in the corner of the garage.
All right, you guys take these.
Go turn the switch on.
What, why us?
We don't know anything
about generators.
Because I need to be
here with my daughter.
Um, okay, he, he, he's right.
Okay, we don't know
what we're doing,
so why don't you take him
and I'll stay with her.
Okay, let's go.
After this, team meeting.
Uh, okay, just um,
stay there.
S- so, uh, Charm's dad,
is he, is he in the picture?
I cut him out a long time ago.
Doesn't stop him
from squirming in
every now and then, but...
Shit. Can you
give me some light?
Uh-huh.
You know, I think the
whole body positivity thing
is super hot.
Hello? Charm?
Are you all right?
Like, if you need help,
if something's wrong,
like, really wrong,
you just have to tell me.
Charm?
Help me, Mama.
O- okay, just, just, just
wait a second! You guys!
Team meeting, all right.
Charm?
Charm? Can you follow my voice?
Can you follow my voice?
I'll go as far as I can, but
you're gonna have to meet me.
Charm, are you coming?
Our Father Who art in
heaven, hallowed be Thy name.
The Lord is my shepherd,
I shall not want.
Charm?
Hello?
Hurry, open this door!
Hurry, open the fucking door!
Somebody open this door!
We got you. Hey, hey.
Oh no.
There is, there
is something out there.
-What?
-Okay, maybe there is.
There's a tunnel all the way
to your damn mailbox, okay?
-Come here, come here.
-well, where's Charm?
-Something was chasing me.
-Charm. Charm.
Ice tunnel?
Yes. Go look, I swear!
What the fuck?
Something is wrong here.
Have you been seeing things.
With all the pills
I've been taking,
I don't think I'm
seeing enough things.
Look, I'm being serious!
Yeah, and I'm
being logical, dude.
Like, we're all tired and
hungry and fucking horny, okay?
So I think some minor
freakouts are allowed.
She drugged us.
What?
I was fine until we ate
and then, and then I, I,
-I thought I saw.
-Oh, no, no, no.
I ate the same thing you did.
Maybe it's too
busy bouncing off
all the other crap
in your system.
Yeah, and maybe
it's like the time
you saw St. Anthony
in the shower.
Look, you want me to
concur with something?
I'll concur that Charm is a
few bats short of a belfry.
Or is it too many bats?
It's too many bats, right?
I think she's here
against her will.
The, the seizures, the
door. It, it makes sense.
No, it do-
I, I talked to her, okay.
She would've told me if she
was a, like a fucking hostage.
It's my face. Makes
girls wanna open up.
-Ugh.
-Don't. Hey, don't, okay?
Your neurotic hunch
is gonna put us
in a freeze-to-death situation.
So you would ignore a
captive human to stay warm?
I am disabled.
Just get some
rest, okay, Nancy Drew?
We're hitting the slopes
tomorrow, no skis.
You know, when
they delivered you,
both of your lungs collapsed,
and the umbilical cord
wrapped around your
neck was not helping.
You weighed two pounds.
When they tried to check you
out in the corner of the room,
the power died,
and I didn't know
what was happening.
You know, I was so
disoriented from the drugs,
theirs and my own.
I didn't know what was going on,
but I could hear them talking
and they were talking about
you like you were already dead.
And I knew that I
couldn't be there for you,
that you would have to
be your own battery,
your own safety, your own charm,
but this time, this time,
I'm here to pull
you out of the dark.
The substitute compound is
making her more aggressive.
I might have to,
I might have to. Fuck!
Fuck.
Hello.
Uh, uh, fuck.
Just leave you there.
Um, um, um.
Oh, Jesus, you're the man.
What the fuck?
Jesus Christ, Faith.
What?
Make the pain go away, my ass.
Idiot.
Mine now.
Okay.
Shit, I got it.
Sorry.
Some, uh,
it's a crazy day, huh?
Still early,
isn't it, buddy?
Oh, oh, uh, you're, um.
Charm's father,
man of the house. That's me.
She didn't really, uh, she
didn't really mention you.
Really? Sounds like
sour teenage grapes to me.
Well, I wouldn't know
I, um, I don't have any kids.
Not yet,
but you got plenty
of that pure white venom
just itching to get out.
I can
smell it from here.
You know, I never
apologized t-, um,
to you for sort of
just dropping in here.
So sorry.
I should go back to bed. So,
um, sorry to wake you up here.
Kory.
Yeah?
You've got
something of mine.
I'm sorry. I, I wasn't gonna.
Nighty-night.
What the fuck?
Don't go out there.
I have to see her for myself.
Trust me, hey. It's not safe.
Well, maybe she's
not safe, either.
Who fucking cares?
That sickening lack of
empathy for your fellow man
is gonna come for
you tenfold, brother,
so do yourself a favour
and get with the program
before it's too late.
Move.
Charm?
It's me, Liz.
Yeah, I know where you are.
Come to stare at
the basket case?
Old school. Nice.
Literally been in
hundreds of those things,
but I still don't
understand how they work.
Photo chemicals are basically
popped like a pimple
onto a positive sheet
when the exposure exits.
After that,
what you see is what you get
or what you thought you saw.
Mystery solved.
I brought you these.
Th- they're very striking.
Thought you might want them.
Liz, right?
Last time I checked, there's
only one copy of that key.
I had to see for myself.
See what for yourself?
That you weren't
here against your will.
The seizure, the door,
the, the, the tunnel.
The tunnel.
Take my picture.
Your home is odd.
I've been keeping my eyes open.
Usually there'll
be a sign somewhere.
You know, a trinket, a symbol.
Some evidence of-
Evidence of what?
Faith.
Hmm. Value judgements from
the home invader, hmm?
I'm sorry. I just...
I- is there something
that you wanna tell me
about your mother?
I've seen situations
like this before.
This isn't how real
protection works.
What's there to tell?
My mom thinks I
turn into a monster
if I get too hot or too cold.
Well, do you?
Joking.
I really, your mother seemed
to have this overdeveloped
sense of duty when it
comes to your health.
Sometimes people want us to
think that their transgressions
are powered by passion.
Then what's actually
in the tank, hmm?
I don't know. Guilt, maybe.
You two sure seem
fascinated by the G word.
I just wish we agreed
on its functions.
Guilt is a stain
bestowed upon people
who make the wrong decisions.
It's the whole point. It's
what separates us from beasts.
So if I really am a monster,
my mom shouldn't feel
guilty for locking me up,
tranquilized like a beast?
Charm, I've seen monsters.
You're not one of them.
Charm.
What you see is what you get.
That's, that's enough.
Charm!
Hey, I don't know
what just happened.
You don't have to tell me. But,
um, we obviously have to go.
I don't know what
the fuck that is.
Look.
Listen, we're gonna get,
we're gonna get some blankets
and then we're gonna steal
some food and then we go out
the way we came in and we
just move faster than shit.
I can't. We can't.
Hey, Lizzie. Hey,
hey, hey, Lizzie.
I know you think you
can help these people.
That's why you're,
you're amazing.
Whatever's happening
in this house is so big
and dark that even a
fucking idiot like me
knows you cannot pray it away.
We're all she has.
Fuck, no, Liz! Pack your shit.
Lizzie, I'll leave you.
Turning our back on
her would be a sin
that dwarves all others.
What do you wanna do?
I wanna vanquish the demon.
The substitute compound is
making her more aggressive.
I might have to,
I might have to. Fuck!
Every medicinal compound
ever created is just a litany
of chemicals that either
trigger, inhibit,
or neutralize until the
desired effect is reached.
There's no precedent
for what we face,
and this holding pattern
is becoming more harmful
to her than the real thing.
The real thing.
Maybe just a micro dose
to get us through the storm.
Hey, Faith. Hey.
What is going on?
Nothing.
-Hmm?
-Yeah, I, I swear.
You swear.
I thought you Jesus freaks
weren't supposed to do that.
Well, I'm kind of a failure
of being a Jesus freak.
So she, um, she just
wants to help, okay?
Charm has begun to
experience blackouts
along with an extreme
personality disorder
in which her body
physically alters.
I have tracked a
continuous high fever,
noting flashes of clarity
between 102 and 104.4 degrees.
We'll attempt to maintain
that 2.4 degree safe zone
via a controlled
methadone overdose.
That's extremely
questionable parenting.
Yesterday, I would've called
that plain manic overkill,
but today?
Porcupines, though?
What kind of fever conjures
farm animals out of thin air?
Mm, porcupines aren't
farm animals, Liz.
Kory!
Liz.
You know there's a theory
that 10% is what we
use of our brains
and that full capacity
operation could be the result
in unlocking of powers like
telepathy, telekinesis,
that'd mean we'd only be
limited by our imagination.
I don't know, it's kinda
like the Green Lantern,
right, but without the rings?
Don't try to tell us the same
lies you tell her, Faith.
We know better.
There are documented studies
of drastic physical transitions.
I could show you.
Your room was interesting.
That lab you got there is
rudimentary to say the least.
Fuck you.
Tell me about your compound,
Faith, about your cure.
Fuck you.
Fine. We'll just skip
to the lightning round.
You might out of methadone,
but your garage is
stocked full, huh?
Fucking antifreeze?
Two questions.
What kind of mother pumps her
little girl full of this shit?
And what kind of little
girl gets pumped full
of this shit and doesn't die?
Admit your hand in this,
Faith, and convince me
that there is something at
work here other than the devil.
The devil. You little bitch.
You don't know shit.
You don't know what it's
like to pull yourself out
from the brink, to pull
your baby out, too,
with no help, no one.
Just the storm and
the resentment.
You don't know what it's
like to be a mother!
So you can take your good book
and your fairy tale
fucking holiday!
You mean Christmas?
And your Ten Commandments.
It's the season of His birth.
And you can go straight to hell!
That spiked bat wasn't
meant for us, was it?
You're scared.
How many more weapons do you
have stashed around here?
You have taken this as far
as you can go. Further, even.
What are you holding onto?
What is the sin whose
shadow in which you live?
It is time to put
your confidence
in something other than
yourself for her sake.
Just say the word.
You want my blessing?
Yes. Yes, I do.
Don't touch her.
If you fucking touch her...
It'll be painless, Faith.
We just invoke His name
and we let Him decide
who's right or wrong,
our truth or your poison.
Don't lay a finger on her.
Don't you fucking touch her!
Kory.
Get out!
-is Christ the King
-Get out of here!
Stop!
Get back here.
Get back!
Get out! Mom!
-Mom!
-Coming!
No!
Mom!
Oh, fuck!
Breathe. Apply pressure.
Okay. Okay, so we're oh for one.
You're never gonna
convince her you're right.
Your sister was
right about one thing.
I am shooting in the dark.
Fever is all that I have.
I just, I have to get control.
Well, you had control,
but now it does.
We gotta leave her.
No, no!
All right, well, um, uh, uh,
Liz's stun gun in her bag maybe?
I won't let anyone else
ever hurt her again!
Hey, hey, somebody. Liz!
Wait!
P- pl- please, please don't go.
Good luck, Nightingale.
Shit. Shit.
Oh!
Okay, fuck.
Where is she?
Tell me she's not out there.
Oh God, Jesus.
What if,
what if He won't take me?
Then you just come on back.
When you said you
made mistakes before,
was I one of them?
No. No, baby.
I, I thought I,
I thought I saw something.
Part of
recovering is letting go.
I would never.
She has this old
suitcase from her party days.
I would never.
No one feels guilty if
they're destroying something
in order to build.
I just can't do this!
I need help!
I can't! Wait, no, I can't!
I don't want to! No!
I can't do it.
I won't fucking do it!
Please, please,
I won't fucking do it.
Please, please, no!
You know,
when they delivered you,
I was so disoriented
from the drugs,
I knew that I
couldn't be there for you,
but this time I'm here
to pull you out the dark.
I'm here to pull
you out of the dark.
Pull you out of the dark.
Come on. Charm!
KLU,
Louisville, Kentucky.
K-top mornings with the bishop.
Get your shorts out, folks.
We got a high of 75 today.
Spring sprung it in January,
a few months early it seems.
there are reports all
over the Louisville area
of flash floodings
melting off the snow
from last week's
white out blizzard,
so be careful out there.
Don't be a stranger over here.
Do you have any
plans this morning?
I'm happy
about it. I'll still-
Gonna add some flowers
to my painting.
You know,
dig into my multimedia bag.
Some, oh, maybe you should
try some gold leafing.
I can help you pick some.
Of course. The more the merrier.
I'll go change.
Okay.
Mom?
Yeah?
Thanks.
For what?
Pulling me out of the dark
like you said you would.
Tell me the worst
thing you've ever done.
I was a bad person.
You're not gonna get a
bigger crown in heaven
trying to save something
that's already lost.
What the fuck are we
doing here then, Liz?
I, I don't believe, I had
a connection, you know?
Yeah, I bet.
No, it's, it's more than that.
It's, it's the, she, I
think she'll listen to me,
so I gotta try.
Kory, she doesn't
want to be saved.
Hey!
Come with me.
I wanna help you.
Mm.
Let's get outta here.
We can leave.
We can go somewhere else.
Shh. Shh.
I'm gonna cum so hard when
I pop your fucking cherry.
What are you doing?
Faith. Faith, what the
fuck, what the fuck?
I enjoyed
corrupting innocence.
Somebody help!
You hammer,
I'll see to his knee, and we'll
figure out the rest later.
Who are you now?
Our little home invader?
Charm, it's me, Liz.
Yeah, I know who you are
Uh, this is Liz and that's Kory.
Take your fucking medicine!
Don't you fucking touch her!
I won't let anyone else
ever hurt her again!
I can't keep this up.
Wait.
You stay back!
You get away!
Please, please don't go.
Please.
No one's getting
out of this zoo.