[epic festive music plays]
♪ Deck the hall with boughs of holly
Fa la la la la, la la la la ♪
♪ 'Tis the season to be jolly
♪ Don we now our gay apparel
Fa la la, fa la la, la la la ♪
♪ Toll the ancient Christmas carol
Fa la la la la, la la la la ♪
Ah, Christmas Eve in London!
- [woman] Oh!
- Who in the world could resist it?
♪ I love Christmas ♪
♪ It's my favorite time of year ♪
♪ So enthralling
To see the snowflakes falling ♪
♪ To hear the children calling
Sweet words of Christmas cheer ♪
♪ It's music to my ears ♪
♪ Fa la la la la, la la la la ♪
♪ See the blazing yule before us
Fa la la la la, la la la la ♪
♪ Strike the harp and join the chorus
♪ Sing we joyous all together
Fa la la, fa la la, la la la ♪
♪ Heedless of the wind and weather
Fa la la la la, la la la la ♪
♪ Church bells ringing
And people singing ♪
♪ Songs of Christmases gone by ♪
♪ Memories that fill the Christmas sky ♪
♪ Love and laughter
Reminding me forever after ♪
♪ Just why I love Christmas ♪
[women laugh]
[jolly music continues]
♪ J-Jingle bells a-jingling
Festive folks a-mingling ♪
♪ Christmas kids a-tingling with delight ♪
♪ As they picture Santa
And his reindeer canter ♪
♪ On their fabled fantasy of flight ♪
Whoo!
♪ Church bells ringing
And people singing ♪
♪ Songs of Christmases gone by ♪
♪ Memories that fill the Christmas sky ♪
♪ Love and laughter
Reminding me forever after ♪
♪ Just why I love ♪
♪ Christmas! ♪
[kids] ♪ Da-da, da-da ♪
♪ Da-da, da-da, da-da, da-da ♪
Yeah!
[bells tinkle]
[magical tinkling]
♪ Deck the hall with boughs of holly
Fa la la la la, la la la la ♪
♪ 'Tis the season to be jolly
[kids groan]
Kathy, the coin!
- Quick, Tim. Catch it!
- [Tim] No.
I-I can't see it.
[gasps] Oi, ratbag!
[sniffs and growls]
Why don't you watch where you're walking,
you great clumsy lump!
[sinister music plays]
Sorry, Mr. Scrooge, sir.
Didn't realize it was you.
- [dog panting]
- [Tim strains]
Good dog.
[dog panting]
[giggles]
Prudence, stop licking that poor boy.
You've no idea where he's been. [laughs]
[ghostly whisper] Scrooge.
[Scrooge whistles] Come now, Prudence.
[Prudence grumbles and barks]
Bye.
Uncle?
Uncle Ebenezer, is that you?
[gasps]
[cheerful music plays]
[growls quizzically]
[jaunty music plays]
[sighs] That was close.
Uncle, it is you! I knew it.
Merry Christmas.
[sighs] And where is she?
Where's the finest lady in all of London?
Prudence, girl.
You grow more beautiful
with every passing year.
Is Uncle Scrooge
taking good care of you, is he?
You don't miss
that rotten old Jacob Marley too much?
Why, I was just on my way
to your office, Uncle.
What luck to run into you.
Well, Harry, they say
a man makes his own luck.
So I suppose I only have myself
to blame for this encounter.
[bell tolls]
Out of time, Jenkins.
[sad music plays]
Good girl. Oh, yes.
There it is.
Yeah, there's a good girl. Yes.
[carolers play "Good King Wenceslas"]
- Care to make a donation?
- To the festive fund for the poor?
- Just enough to make Christmas merry.
- Or perhaps a little bit more?
[both chuckle]
Do you have a permit to perform here?
We didn't know we needed one.
Did you know we needed one?
I didn't know we needed one.
We didn't know we needed one.
Well, now you know you need one.
So pack up your trumpets,
before I call the police...
[music fades]
...to throw you all in prison,
leaving me in peace.
Good day, ladies. [laughs]
[ghostly whisper] Scrooge...
[both] How rude!
Uncle! Uncle!
Oh, splendid.
- Uh, here you go.
- Oh!
Thank you very much, sir. Such generosity.
Such generosity. Thank you very much, sir.
Think nothing of it.
Why, who would be
uncharitable at Christmas?
[both scoff] Who indeed.
Uncle. Wait for us!
I swear I had your money in hand
yesterday, Mr. Scrooge.
It's just that my mother, she got sick,
you see, and I had to pay for a doctor.
Another fascinating story, Jenkins.
But here's a better one.
Once upon a time,
Tom Jenkins, that's you,
owed me, Ebenezer Scrooge, 25 pounds.
Jenkins paid the money in full,
and Scrooge lived happily ever after.
The end.
Oh, come on now, Mr. Scrooge, sir.
I don't have it right now,
but I'm sure I can scrape it together
in another three, four days.
Five. A week.
- Come on, it is Christmas after all.
- [toy trumpet plays]
[laughter]
Louder.
Faster!
- He's rubbish.
- [laughter]
Christmas? Really? If only I'd known.
This changes everything.
Very well, in the spirit of the season,
Mr. Tom Jenkins, you now have
until the end of Boxing Day to pay me.
Two extra days. How does that sound?
Two days is better than nothing,
I suppose.
Thank you very much, Mr. Scrooge.
Most charitable indeed.
Father Christmas has nothing on you.
Ho ho ho, yes, quite.
Now, let's see.
For the inconvenience you have caused me
and the extra two days,
shall we say another 25 pounds?
- That would mean I owe...
- Fifty pounds.
It's a good, round number,
wouldn't you agree?
Well, 30 is a round number too,
Mr. Scrooge.
You're right. But so is 60.
[toy trumpet plays]
When you put it that way,
50 does have a better ring to it.
♪ Two days, Jenkins, then I'll be back ♪
♪ To take my 50 pounds ♪
Do give my best to Mother Jenkins.
Oh, and Tom,
merry Christmas.
Fifty pounds. Two days.
Look out. [groans]
[both] Merry Christmas.
- [ghostly whisper] Scrooge.
- [Scrooge] Hmm?
[Harry] I say, Mr. Jenkins.
Do you deliver?
- [toy squeaks]
- Mr. Jenkins?
[Prudence whines]
[intriguing music plays]
Bah, humbug.
Left a bit. Right a bit. Left a bit again.
Up. No, up.
Left.
Your other left.
There, perfect. You're an artist, Mickey.
An artist would get paid more than a penny
for every thousand posters
he sticks up, Beryl.
You there. Yes, you. Who are you?
What do you think you're doing?
Who, us?
Sir, we is nothing
but a bunch of poor, homeless urchins
trying to make our way in the world.
- [giggling]
- [Scrooge snarls]
Quick. Leg it!
[children laugh]
Merry Christmas! [laughs]
Blooming children.
[magical tinkling]
- [door slams]
- [yelps] Mr. Scrooge. Oh dear.
Welcome back, sir.
There's something I should tell you.
The cost of that ink
will be deducted from your pay.
What? The ink?
Oh. Oh, the ink. Of course, sir, yes.
Get on with your work, Cratchit.
- If it's not too much of an inconvenience.
- But, sir...
- I do not wish to be disturbed.
- [Bob] Yes.
I've had more than my fill
of people for one...
- [toy trumpet plays]
- ...day.
[laughs loudly]
- We win!
- How in the world did you...?
- Prudence knows a shortcut, don't you?
- [barks]
Very well, let's get this over with then,
shall we?
How does it go again?
Oh, yes, yes, the question.
"Uncle, won't you join me
for Christmas dinner tomorrow?"
The answer,
"No, Harry, I will not."
"Christmas is a humbug.
I despise it and all it stands for."
The same answer to the same question
you ask me every year.
I have no time to be merry.
Just because my partner is dead doesn't
mean I have no business to attend to.
Quite the opposite. Jacob Marley died
seven years ago this very night,
leaving me nothing but business.
Oh, yes, and you.
Oh, come now, Uncle.
Hela and I would just love to have you.
Hela? Who's Hela?
You know, Hela, my wife.
She was disappointed
you couldn't attend the wedding,
and simply can't wait to meet you.
So at least visit us this evening.
Some friends and I
are gathering to toast the season.
Good day, Harry.
[whimpers]
Uncle, I'm all the family you have.
Why does it have to be this way?
I think Mother
would have been so disappointed
that you and I
spend every Christmas apart.
[weights clatter]
- [ominous music plays]
- [whimpers]
[Scrooge growls]
Harry, life is full of disappointments.
One such disappointment came
on the glorious Christmas Day
that you stumbled into this world.
The very same Christmas Day your mother,
my beloved sister, left it.
I will not be joining you
for Christmas dinner,
nor any other celebration
of this wretched season.
Now, please leave
before I say something you will regret.
[Scrooge breathes deeply]
[Prudence whimpers and growls]
[mysterious music plays]
[ghostly whisper] Scrooge.
My offer still stands.
You are always welcome, Uncle.
- Goodbye!
- Merry Christmas, Prudence.
- Bob.
- Merry Christmas, sir.
[door closes]
[coughs] Festive, ain't it?
[clears throat] Excuse me, sir,
but it's almost 6:00. Six o'clock.
Could I trouble you for my wages, please?
Cratchit, Cratchit, Cratchit...
you do nothing but trouble me.
- [chuckles] Yeah.
- [Prudence whimpers]
Five, 10, 15 shillings.
- [Bob] Thank you, sir.
- Take away five.
But I'm owed 15.
Consider the other five
your payment to me.
- For what, sir?
- The ink, of course.
And the day off
you insist on taking tomorrow.
Well, sir, it is Christmas.
[barks]
Yes, as everyone is so fond of telling me.
Sir, this isn't enough.
My family, you see, my children...
My... My boy needs medicine.
You have children?
Of course you do.
Cratchit, times are hard.
And my financial burdens are considerable.
Now should I add to them by paying
for the upkeep of your entire family?
- [ghostly whisper] Scrooge...
- [Scrooge] Does that sound fair to you?
No, sir.
No, sir, indeed.
Now, let's get you on your way, shall we?
- Merry Christmas, Mr. Scrooge.
- Yes, yes. Ding-dong, merrily.
I expect you
at half past seven on Boxing Day.
[Prudence growls quietly]
What? What have I done now?
[coughing]
Why, if it isn't the amazing
and wonderful Cratchit children!
[both] Father!
[coughs]
- [gasps] Tim!
- Father, help!
It's all right, my little man.
Just breathe, slowly.
[coughs]
He's getting worse.
That's it. There you go.
Right, you two.
That's it, no more busking tonight.
It's freezing out here,
and you need your rest, young man.
Aw.
- But we've only made ten pence ha'penny.
- Ten pence ha'penny? A bumper windfall!
If we add that to the ten shillings
I happen to have in my pocket
and throw in a bit of Cratchit magic,
I reckon we can have as fine a Christmas
as the Lord Mayor himself.
- [both] Yay!
- [Bob] Just wait and see.
[carolers play "O Come All Ye Faithful"]
[Prudence whimpers]
[sighs]
[Prudence growls]
Oh, don't be so dramatic.
I'll pick up a juicy bone for you
on the way home. How does that sound?
[whines happily]
- The butcher owes me seven pounds six...
- [Prudence scoffs]
...so I'm sure he'll be happy to oblige.
[ghostly whisper] Scrooge...
No?
No pleasing some people.
[carolers play "O Come All Ye Faithful"]
You there. What do you think
you're doing? [laughs]
[children laugh]
[Scrooge snarls]
Oh, bravo!
There you go.
Merry Christmas.
[pained sigh]
[soft music plays]
[grumbles]
[grunts and grumbles]
You two!
Clear off!
Disgusting.
[ghostly whisper] Ebenezer Scrooge...
[intriguing music plays]
[Prudence growls]
[intriguing music continues]
[clock ticks]
♪ Every year, the same reminders ♪
♪ Of the things I've lost ♪
♪ Absent friends and broken pledges ♪
♪ Wrapped in freezing frost ♪
♪ Why should I be bright and merry? ♪
♪ Why should I? Won't someone tell me? ♪
♪ Tell me ♪
Tell me.
[man] There you go, sir.
[Scrooge snarls]
♪ Cold, bleak winters filled with sorrow ♪
♪ All I've ever known ♪
♪ Season's greetings? ♪
♪ You can keep them ♪
♪ Just leave me alone ♪
[ghostly whisper] Scrooge.
♪ "Why not join us, toast the season?" ♪
♪ Don't they know I have my reasons? ♪
♪ Tell me ♪
♪ Every year, such joy and gladness ♪
♪ Sparkling in their eyes ♪
♪ Treat them tougher ♪
♪ Make them suffer ♪
♪ Bring them down to size ♪
♪ All around me ♪
♪ Oh, so cheery ♪
♪ I'm not happy, so why should they be? ♪
♪ Tell me ♪
Tell me!
Ahh!
[yells]
[whimpers]
[ominous music plays]
[ghostly whisper] Ebenezer Scrooge.
[gasps]
Ebenezer Scrooge.
[ominous music continues]
[whimpers]
- [Scrooge whimpers]
- [Prudence barks]
[clock ticks]
[howls]
[breathes heavily]
[barks]
[eerie music plays]
[metal thuds]
[magical tinkling]
[eerie music continues]
[eerie music intensifies]
[Scrooge whimpers]
Ebenezer Scrooge.
[eerie music fades]
J-J-J-Jacob Marley?
Impossible. You're dead.
Dead?
Dead tired! [laughs]
- [bones crack]
- Oh.
[Jacob groans]
Oh, yeah. How embarrassing.
- [Prudence growls]
- Prudence. Oh, how well you look. [laughs]
I knew leaving you
in the care of Uncle Scrooge
was the right thing to do, hmm? Didn't I?
Hmm? Yes, I did. I did. [chuckles]
I do apologize
for the dramatic entrance, old boy.
Those in charge
insist on a touch of pageantry.
Goes with the territory, you see.
But I'm sure you and I can discuss
the rest like reasonable men.
Ah, I must have drifted off by the fire.
I'm dreaming.
[laughs] Serves me right
for eating cheese so close to bedtime.
Well,
very well.
[Scrooge chuckles]
[dramatic music plays]
[Scrooge yells]
[gasps]
[Scrooge] Ye gods!
[Jacob] Listen well, Scrooge.
This is no dream.
Look upon the chain that binds me.
In life, I forged it,
link by link, yard by yard.
It grew to match my greed.
In death, I will never be rid of it.
Nor will you yours.
[gasps] Mine?
Yes, yours.
[Scrooge yells and whimpers]
[dramatic music plays]
[Scrooge panting in fear]
[Jacob] We were all like you.
Trapped in our own selfish worlds.
We never reached out
to our fellow men in life,
so are condemned to do so in death.
We have watched you many a day, Scrooge.
Watched your chain grow,
link by link, yard by yard.
But you may yet escape our fate.
I have pulled a few chains
and arranged for three visitors
to call on you before morning.
The first, when the bell tolls 1:00.
The second, at 2:00.
And the third, at...
Well, 3:00.
[Prudence whimpers]
[dramatic music continues]
Listen to these visitors. Learn from them.
And heed my warning
before it's too late.
[Scrooge whimpers]
[dramatic music continues]
[Scrooge yells]
[breathing heavily]
[growls]
[creaking]
[gasps]
[laughs]
Jacob Marley
concerned for someone else's well-being?
Well, it must have been a dream.
[Scrooge chuckles]
[gasps]
Huh?
[magical tinkling]
Humbug.
It's that nephew of mine. Interfering.
Bringing my blood to the boil.
Has me jumping at shadows.
Seeing things. Yes.
That's it. Yes.
[bell tolls in distance]
[Jacob] The first, at 1:00.
[bell tolls]
[creaking]
Hmm.
Hmm. [chuckles]
[whimpers]
[Prudence whines]
[Scrooge groans]
[electricity crackles]
- [magical tinkling]
- [groans]
[intriguing music plays]
[Scrooge gasps]
[Scrooge breathes heavily]
[gasps]
[Prudence whimpers]
[intriguing music continues]
[gasps]
[grumbles]
[intriguing music continues]
- Hello?
- [ghost yelps]
[yelps]
[Scrooge whimpers]
[ghost breathes deeply]
Oh, hello.
It's Scrooge, isn't it?
Yes, that's the one, Scrooge.
[chuckles] What a funny name.
Are you comfortable down there, Scrooge?
Uh, well...
Never mind that.
Who, or what, are you?
And it's "Mr. Scrooge," if you please.
Well, Mr. Scrooge-if-you-please, who am I?
I can be anyone you have ever known.
I can even be you.
[whimpers]
Bah, humbugs.
Christmas is an outrage.
Grr, give me your money.
- Interest rates, and so on.
- Hmm.
You were not told of my coming?
No? No matter.
You have nothing to fear from me.
After all, your welfare is my business.
Miss, to be disturbed at this hour
is hardly conducive to my welfare.
Your redemption, then.
You see, an old friend of yours
asked me to illuminate
a thing or two for you. I...
Illuminate what, exactly?
I was getting to that.
You are an impatient one. [clears throat]
I will show you the past.
Christmas past.
Specifically, your Christmas past. Ahh!
There. Much better.
I've gone mad.
Mad, you say?
Jacob Marley floating in my sitting room.
Faces etched in frost.
Whispers in the wind.
A blizzard indoors.
Now you, a talking waxwork
with a wick for brains.
My dreams are never this... exciting.
And none of this can be real.
So, yes, I must be awake,
but quite insane.
Well, I may have wick for brains,
but I do think I'm real.
Here.
- [growls]
- [Past] Oh, hush now.
There, did that feel real?
I-I suppose it did.
It hurt too.
[chuckles] Yes, the past can hurt.
Especially yours.
But it can also heal,
if you learn from it.
- Now, come with me.
- Absolutely not.
I refuse to go anywhere...
[Past] Whee!
[laughs] Whoo!
Yeah!
[Prudence whimpers]
[Scrooge whimpers]
[Scrooge] No, no!
[whimpers]
[Scrooge yells]
[Past] Whee!
[whimpers]
[yells]
[Past] Whoo!
[epic magical music plays]
[Scrooge yells]
Oh, baby Scrooge!
No!
[epic magical music continues]
[Scrooge screams]
[Scrooge thuds]
[Past] Whoo-hoo!
[clears throat]
Where? W-What? Who?
- [Scrooge groans]
- [Past chuckles]
[Prudence whines]
[Scrooge groans]
[laughs]
Get off!
[grumbles]
[Past laughs]
Sorry, it does take its toll
going this far back.
- Did I not warn you?
- No, you certainly...
Wait, what do you mean by "back"?
Huh?
[man sings backwards]
- What...?
- We're not quite there yet.
Almost.
Here we are.
[magical music plays]
The past. [chuckles]
Spooky! [chuckles]
I know this place.
It was demolished years ago.
I saw to that.
♪ ...looked out on the Feast of Stephen ♪
You there. What day is it?
I say... [groans]
Ah! Oh! Oh!
[chuckles] I wouldn't do that.
You can't interfere with anything here.
And nobody can hear you.
Or see you, for that matter.
[eerie music plays]
- [man] Don't fill it right to the top.
- Look!
Young Ebenezer Scrooge,
hard at work on Christmas Eve.
Not very festive, is it?
I...
I-I had no choice.
You see, without the modest income
I provided, my mother and sister,
th-they would have starved.
- Did your father not have any money?
- My father?
He was not a poor man,
but the fool spent his way
into debtors' prison.
[gasps]
Oh, I see.
Debtors' prison. Terrible, terrible thing,
a debtors' prison.
- What is a debtors' prison again?
- A debtors' prison is, uh...
None of your business.
[jaunty music plays]
[barks]
[Past laughs]
[laughs] You can't escape your past, mate.
Now, look here...
[girl] ♪ The wish that you wish
On Christmas Day ♪
♪ Is pretty well sure to come true
They say ♪
♪ So the wish that I wish you tonight
My friend ♪
♪ May you spend Christmas mornings ♪
- ♪ Without end ♪
- Jen?
♪ Dreaming of a miracle or two ♪
My dear little sister, Jen.
♪ And may all your Christmas wishes ♪
♪ Come true ♪
[coughs]
[Scrooge gasps]
- Jen. Come on, breathe.
- [Jen coughs]
Slowly.
In and out.
That's it.
What are you doing here alone?
- Does Mother know you're out?
- I wanted to give you this.
I made it all by myself.
- Merry Christmas, Ebenezer.
- Oh, Jen. It's Father Christmas.
- He's really magnificent.
- [Jen chuckles]
Maybe you could help me
make one for you in return.
Yes, please! [Jen laughs]
Shall we sing
that pretty song of yours as we walk?
[both] ♪ The wish that you wish
On Christmas Day ♪
♪ Is pretty well sure to come true
They say ♪
Oh, such a sweet child.
Will she be all right?
She will be. For a while, at least,
the sickness will not take her.
My father paid his debts, eventually.
We found the right doctor
and she was saved. But...
[Past] But?
She remained a delicate soul,
whom a breath might have withered.
Jen died in childbirth.
My idiot nephew in exchange for my sister.
A sorry transaction in any currency.
And all on Christmas Day.
Christmas.
Oof. Humbug.
Oh, come now.
Is there not one Christmas
you remember fondly?
One buried, perhaps,
in a hole as deep as old Marley's grave?
Hmm?
- Hmm?
- Hmm.
- Merry Christmas, sir.
- [Scrooge groans]
Hello, Uncle.
[barks]
- [exclaims]
- [Scrooge yelps]
Aha!
I do believe I've found one.
Mr. Fezziwig.
"Fizzywig?" Why, that's almost
as silly as "Scrooge."
Off we go.
- A little jump forward this time.
- Wait...
[magical music plays]
[sighs] I'm home then.
And not before time.
Very well. You have a week and no more.
Or we shall both
have to find new employment.
- Good day.
- Thank you very much, Mr. Scrooge.
God bless ya.
And a merry Christmas when it comes.
[grumbles] It's still the past.
It is.
My word, you were
a handsome chap, Scrooge.
What went wrong?
[Fezziwig] Ebenezer?
Is that you, lad?
- Mr. Fezziwig?
- [Fezziwig] It is you!
Wonderful to see you, my boy.
[Past] So that's Mr. Wizzyfig.
Fezziwig. Yes, I used to work
in his warehouse before Marley took me on.
Why didn't you keep working for him?
Marley offered a position
with more security.
People will always need money.
If I'd stayed, I would only have been
Fezziwig's lowly apprentice.
I had to better myself
before even thinking of proposing to her.
Proposing?
Oh, I do like a wedding.
Who's her? Where's her?
[Fezziwig] Flora!
Isabel.
Yes, Father?
[romantic music plays]
- Isabel.
[Fezziwig] Look who I found!
Ebenezer! How lovely to see you.
My, you look splendid in your suit.
- Although, do you mind?
- I... I...
- That is...
- There.
- You see...
- Perfect.
Thank you.
Oh, Isabel, how I love thee.
With thy big slobbery face
and stinking dog breath.
Oh! Oh.
Uh, Ebenezer, do you have
any plans for tomorrow?
- Tomorrow, sir?
- You know, Christmas Day, my boy!
No, sir. My sister
is with her husband in Kent.
They're expecting a child any day now.
She invited me to visit,
but I had to decline.
[laughs] Then it's decided!
You'll join us
for Christmas lunch tomorrow.
I'm not sure I can.
Too much still to be done, and Mr. Marley
doesn't even take the day himself.
Say you'll come, Ebenezer.
It'll be such fun.
[Past] Oh, look away.
I, uh...
I'll talk to Mr. Marley.
- Did you go?
- Well, it would have been rude not to.
I felt obliged.
I see.
See you there.
But you didn't enjoy it?
No. Not one bit.
Hmm.
[joyful fiddle music plays]
- [laughs] Oh my goodness.
- [Scrooge laughs]
You look like you're having an awful time.
[joyful music continues]
[Scrooge gasps and music stops]
[one note plays]
Uh, yes.
[romantic fiddle music plays]
♪ They say happiness
Is a thing you can't see ♪
♪ A thing you can't touch, I disagree ♪
♪ Happiness is the folly of fools ♪
♪ Pity poor me, one of those fools ♪
♪ Happiness is standing beside me ♪
♪ I can see him ♪
♪ He can see me ♪
♪ Happiness is whatever
You want it to be ♪
♪ They say happiness
Is a thing you can't see ♪
♪ A thing you can't touch, I disagree ♪
♪ Happiness is the folly of fools ♪
♪ Pity poor me, one of those fools ♪
♪ Happiness is smiling upon me ♪
♪ Walking my way, sharing my day ♪
♪ Happiness is whatever
You want it to be ♪
[both] ♪ Happiness is a bright star ♪
♪ Are we happy? Yes, we are ♪
♪ Happiness is a clear sky ♪
♪ Give me wings and just ♪
♪ Just let me fly ♪
♪ Let me fly ♪
[Past] A delightful woman.
Without her,
Jen's death would have taken
an even greater toll on me.
You married her, yes?
[Scrooge] No. Not quite. I...
No?
- I would very much like to see why not.
- No!
[magical whooshing]
[Scrooge groans]
I...
I do wish you would stop doing that.
Home. Finally.
Well, goodbye, whatever you are.
I would say it's been a pleasure,
but it hasn't.
Where's my name?
[Isabel hums]
This is before Marley made me a partner.
Ebenezer? Hello?
- I'm still in the past.
- [Isabel] Hello?
Oh, you do catch on quickly, don't you?
[Prudence barks]
Ebenezer? Are you there?
I brought some lunch.
I see so little of you these days,
so I thought...
[sighs] I'm not sure what I thought.
Ah, lovely Isabel.
- But you said you didn't marry her?
- We are...
Were merely engaged. For quite some time.
I see. I thought you would have
gone back to work for Wiggyfiz?
Of course not!
His charity would have led to the same
ruination that befell my family.
"His charity would have led
to the same ruination
that befell my blah, blah, blah."
[grunts]
I needed more security
than he could offer. We needed it.
I saw them by the baker's
only a few minutes ago. Good day.
[grumbles] Lead on, Scrooge.
Lead on. Allons-y.
[baby cries]
Please, Mr. Marley, sir.
This is my livelihood. My home.
My family will starve. Just one more week.
One more day,
and I'll have your money, I swear.
You've had three weeks already.
I am sorry.
No. No apologies, Ebenezer.
Times are hard,
and my financial burdens are considerable.
Should I add to them by paying
for the upkeep of your entire family?
Does that sound fair to you?
- Sir, it's Christmas Eve.
- Come on.
Please, show some mercy.
- [woman] Where are you taking him?
- [man] Clear off. Go on. On your way!
[Scrooge] ...and my financial burdens
are considerable.
Now should I add to them by paying
for the upkeep of your entire family?
Does that sound fair to you, Cratchit?
I... I don't recall this at all.
I'm not surprised.
As horrible as this situation is,
I'm sure it was of great financial benefit
to you and Marley.
Apart from the delightful Miss Fizzlejig,
you only seem to remember encounters
where you lose money.
You dwell on the bad things in life,
and then learn nothing from them.
Does Cratchit know?
Why would he choose to work for me?
After what I...
If his father had only paid his debts...
[Jacob laughs]
It's not my fault.
[gasps] Isabel.
[Isabel sniffs]
She saw all of this.
[magical tinkling]
[knocking at door]
[Isabel] Ebenezer.
Can I talk to you?
Alone.
[sighs] Not now, Isabel.
I have far too much work.
Later, later.
[Jacob chuckles]
I'll, uh, leave you two lovebirds to it.
- [growls]
- [Jacob] Come, Boris.
[melancholy music plays]
No.
[melancholy music continues]
♪ When we first met ♪
♪ Your heart was free ♪
♪ Your hopeful eyes ♪
♪ Saw only me ♪
♪ Now you're looking for something ♪
♪ Something I can never be ♪
♪ When you are really ♪
♪ All I need ♪
♪ You keep on telling me "later" ♪
♪ But "later" never comes around ♪
♪ Please stop telling me "later" ♪
♪ As you search
For what just can't be found ♪
♪ Take my hand ♪
♪ Come with me now and we'll fly free ♪
♪ No more "later"
We both know that's a lie ♪
♪ Don't let this be the day I say ♪
♪ Goodbye ♪
♪ When you met her ♪
♪ You were set free ♪
♪ Her love for you ♪
♪ Was plain to see ♪
♪ You kept looking for something ♪
♪ A measure of security ♪
♪ But she was really ♪
♪ All you'd need ♪
♪ You kept on telling her "later" ♪
♪ But "later" never comes around ♪
♪ Please stop telling her "later" ♪
♪ Stop searching for what can't be found ♪
♪ Take her hand ♪
♪ Go with her now and you'll fly free ♪
♪ No more "later"
We both know that's a lie ♪
♪ This will be the day she says ♪
♪ Goodbye ♪
[Isabel] ♪ Goodbye ♪
- ♪ Goodbye ♪
[music fades]
[Jacob] Ebenezer?
Some assistance, please.
Yes, Jacob, coming.
Later, Isabel.
No!
There is no "later!"
Goodbye, Ebenezer.
[sad music plays]
[Past] Oh, look.
A wee glimpse into Isabel's future.
Oh, she looks so happy.
And her husband's gorgeous.
That... That could have been you, I suppose.
Oh, too bad, Scrooge. Too bad.
Why show me all of this now?
What's done is done. I can't go back.
When we were financially secure,
I would have married her...
eventually.
Wouldn't I?
I don't know.
- [magical tinkling]
- [gasps]
- [Scrooge yells]
- Bye!
Take me back.
Take me back!
I'm afraid I can't.
There is no going back,
nor changing what has been.
You said so yourself.
You can't change the past,
but you can learn from it.
For your own sake, I hope you do, Scrooge.
- Ooh.
- [Scrooge] No, no, no, no!
Whoo! It really is time to go.
Farewell, Scrooge.
Farewell. [laughs]
No, please! Don't leave me here!
I must.
Ooh. I have shown you what was.
Now another will show you what is.
Oh. Ooh.
Remember what you have seen, Scrooge.
Remember. Learn.
Change while you still can!
[Scrooge yells]
[Jacob] The second, at 2:00.
[dramatic music plays]
[Scrooge yells]
[music stops]
[eerie music plays]
[Scrooge yells]
[Scrooge groans]
[groans]
Hello?
Is there anybody there?
[snoring]
[Scrooge] Strange, annoying,
candle lady thing?
Hello?
Huh?
[gasps and groans]
[dramatic music plays]
[cheerlings squeaking]
[gasps]
Who dares disturb my slumber?
[dramatic music continues]
State thy name and business, puny mortal.
[cheerlings squeak]
[laughs] I can't...
I can't... I can't keep it up.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
- It was her. She dared me.
- [cheerling laughs]
Oh, we do like to have fun here.
Don't worry.
I know who you are.
Come on, bring it in,
Ebenezer Scrooge. Bring it in!
- [Scrooge groans]
- Welcome, my friend. Welcome.
Welcome where?
Where am I?
When am I?
Oh, you are in the here and now.
In the present!
Isn't it just fabulous?
[cheerlings squeak]
It's fine, I suppose.
From here, I can go anywhere I please.
Just so long as it's happening right now.
And I do so love to visit
your teeny-tiny, tootsy-wootsy,
little planet at this time of year.
So much love, generosity, and good cheer!
Which, conversely, brings me to you.
- Me?
- Yes, you.
Squeezing, wrenching, grasping,
clutching, covetous you!
[magical tinkling]
Secret and solitary as an oyster,
you edge along the crowded paths of life
keeping everyone at a distance.
[magical tinkling]
Why, you stopped truly living your life
so long ago, you might as well be dead.
Do not presume
to tell me how to live my life.
I lead a good life.
I'm a good man. [grunts]
[Present] Ha! "A good man," he says.
Uh, uh, uh.
[rapping] ♪ Ebenezer Scrooge ♪
♪ The sins of man are huge ♪
♪ A never-ending symphony
Of villainy and infamy ♪
♪ Of mischief, mayhem, misery
Deceit and subterfuge ♪
♪ And no one's worse than you
Mr. Ebenezer Scrooge ♪
♪ But while the likes of you
Make life seem like a living hell ♪
♪ You know, life has
A brighter side as well, whoo! ♪
[singing] ♪ I like life, life likes me ♪
♪ Life and I fairly fully agree ♪
♪ Life is fine, life is good ♪
♪ Especially mine
Which is just as it should be ♪
♪ I like life, here and now ♪
♪ Life and I made a mutual vow ♪
♪ Till I die, life and I ♪
♪ We'll both try to be better somehow ♪
♪ Yes, I like living the life
And why not? ♪
♪ 'Cause life's a pleasure ♪
♪ That I deny not ♪
♪ I like life ♪
Whoo!
♪ Life likes me ♪
♪ I make life a perpetual spree ♪
♪ Eating food, drinking wine ♪
♪ Thinking who'd like
The privilege to join me ♪
♪ I like life, you should too ♪
♪ Just live life
Spreading cheer while you do ♪
♪ Life is short, make it count ♪
♪ There's no problem
That can't be surmounted ♪
♪ Live your life unafraid ♪
♪ Just give in ♪
♪ ‘Cause life's a wonderful thing ♪
♪ For living ♪
♪ Life ♪
♪ Oh, yes, I like ♪
♪ Life! ♪
[cheerling swoons and squeals]
[laughs loudly]
Do you see the light?
Can you feel it, Scrooge?
Are you ready to live your life,
now, in the present,
unencumbered by the weight of the past?
[exciting music plays]
I'm ready.
I'm ready to go home. Thank you very much.
[music fades]
Oh, really?
But the fireworks.
We did a whole song and everything.
Well, I'm not giving up on you yet,
Ebenezer Scrooge.
Come on. Let's hit the town.
Hit the town?
I'll hit something else in a minute.
Dragged from pillar to post
in the middle of the night. Huh.
[laughter]
[cheerlings squeak]
- [Prudence barks]
- [cheerlings squeak]
My friends, please.
I-I would like to propose a toast.
My friends, please. Oh...
Oh, thank you.
He really is a buffoon, that boy.
There's no need to whisper.
No one can hear or see you.
- [Scrooge gasps]
- Lucky them. [laughs]
Please raise your glass
and drink to the good health and long life
of my celebrated uncle, Ebenezer Scrooge.
- [crowd mutter]
- [woman] Boo.
I know. I know.
But I like old Scrooge.
- No, no, no. No. Come now. I do. I do.
- [woman] Why?
Why?
I never met my mother,
but my father spoke of her often.
Of her kindness. Her generosity.
It's hard to believe
that the woman he described
was that old stick-in-the-mud's
little sister. [chuckles]
But his sister she was.
And, by all accounts,
she and my uncle were inseparable.
She loved him without reservation,
and he, her.
So he can't be all bad.
I have to believe that somewhere
in that loathsome old carcass of his,
the man my mother loved
is fighting to get out.
I should like to meet him one day.
Which brings me to my next toast
of the evening, to my beloved mother.
As I entered the world, you departed.
Here's to the Christmases we never shared,
and the sad, short one we did.
[sad music plays]
Harry, my dear, sweet Harry,
let's not dwell
on the sadness in our past,
on those who cannot be with us.
- Or refuse to be.
- [cheerling squeaks]
Instead, let us celebrate
those who are here.
Hear! Hear!
[cheerling squeals]
Everyone, let us honor the past
by toasting our present.
To each other. To Christmas.
- To friendship.
- [man 1] Hear! Hear!
- [man 2] To friendship.
- To friendship.
[woman] To friendship.
Bravo!
[mysterious music plays]
[Scrooge sighs]
[jaunty music plays]
Oh, for goodness' sake,
where are we going now?
[Present] May I present to you
the beautiful home
of Robert Cratchit Esquire.
He owes these sumptuous surroundings
to the generosity of his employer.
I never knew
Cratchit had quite so many children.
No? Did you ever ask him?
Mmm. Pure nectar. An elixir
fit for Father Christmas himself.
The stuffing's ready, Father.
- [both] And the birdie is plucked.
- Tremendous work, my dears.
Roast goose with sage and onion stuffing
à la Cratchit.
A legendary gourmet dish.
[laughter]
There's one problem. I'm not sure whether
to stuff the goose with the stuffing,
or stuff the stuffing with the goose.
[Mrs. Cratchit sighs]
Come now, my love.
It is a lean Christmas,
there's no denying that.
But we have each other
and we have the children.
We can still make the most of it.
In fact, I do believe this will be
the best Cratchit Christmas ever.
[children] Hooray!
[children cheering]
- [clears throat]
- [spoon taps]
Not another toast.
If you please,
a toast to those whose generosity
have made possible
tomorrow's sumptuous Christmas feast.
Master Timothy and Miss Katherine,
the Christmas-caroling Cratchits,
of course.
And Mr. Ebenezer Scrooge.
Oh! Scrooge?
What are you trying to do,
spoil our Christmas?
But his money paid for the goose, my dear.
No, your money paid for the goose.
- If you can even call that a goose.
- But he paid me the money.
Because you earned it.
Believe me, you earned that money, Bob.
Mr. Scrooge assures me
that times are hard, my dear.
Times are hard. For us, not him.
Nonetheless, he is the founder
of our feast, and we should drink to him.
Hear! Hear!
The founder of our feast indeed.
I'd like to give him
something to feast on.
He'd have indigestion all January.
[children laugh]
[sighs] Children, we shall drink
to your father.
For the love and happiness he brings us.
And to our Tiny Tim,
for the health we wish him.
And, for the sake of your dear father,
I will even drink
to that old miser, Mr. Scrooge.
Long life to him and to us all.
And a merry Christmas to us all.
[children] Merry Christmas!
God bless us.
God bless us, every one.
[children] Merry Christmas!
I think Bob Cratchit's rather fond of me.
So is his wife.
Couldn't you tell? [chuckles]
And now, to the triumphant
musical climax of this celebration.
Master Timothy, Miss Katherine,
would you be so kind?
- No.
- [children] Sing, sing!
Go on, love. Sing, sing!
It's embarrassing.
Sing!
I will if Kathy does.
[Kathy sighs]
[gentle music plays]
♪ On the beautiful day
That I dream about ♪
♪ There's a world I would love to see ♪
♪ It's a beautiful place
Where the sun comes out ♪
♪ And it shines in the sky for me ♪
♪ On this beautiful day
That I dream about ♪
♪ There's no place I would rather be ♪
♪ On this beautiful winter's morning ♪
♪ If my wish could come true somehow ♪
♪ Then the beautiful day
That I dream about ♪
♪ Would be here ♪
♪ And now ♪
[coughs]
Timmy.
Oh, just breathe. Slowly. That's it.
- That's it.
- [Tim coughs]
There we go.
Slowly.
[ominous music plays]
[cheerlings squeal]
[Prudence barks]
Bob's boy, Tim.
What will become of him?
The future is as much a mystery to me
as it is to you.
I can only show you what is.
What's to come if you do not change?
Well, that will soon be revealed
by... someone else.
[cheerlings squeal]
- [Prudence barks]
- [cheerling laughs]
[cheerling squeals]
[burps] Oh, excuse me.
Look, friend, there really is
no great secret to any of this.
You just have to do
the best you can with the time you have.
But you better get started soon.
Because before you know it,
all that time you think you have
will run out.
[ominous music plays]
[bell tolls]
[Jacob] The third, at 3:00.
- [thunder crashes]
- [bell tolls]
[thunder crashes]
[bell tolls]
[Scrooge gasps]
Well, goodbye, Ebenezer Scroo...
Ooh! [chuckles]
Would you look at that?
- [gasps and groans]
- [Scrooge gasps]
[dramatic music plays]
[Scrooge gasps]
[cheerlings squeak]
[fearling laughs]
[dramatic music continues]
[fearlings laugh]
[whimpers]
[Scrooge gasps]
[fearlings laugh]
[dramatic music fades]
- [Prudence whimpers]
- I, uh...
[fearlings laugh]
We are no longer in the present.
This is the future.
This is what is yet to come.
Are you still in there, giant?
The fellow in the green robes?
Liked life and so forth?
No.
You are something else entirely.
You don't speak?
Your colleagues were
rather fond of speaking.
More than I would have liked.
So you are the one that will show me
what awaits if I do not change my ways.
Yes?
[eerie rustling]
So I should change, should I?
Why? Tell me.
I live my life as well as I can.
I have my faults, but who does not, truly?
Are all others
I've been shown this night without blame?
Am I the only one
with the power to change my life?
To change the lives of others?
Well? Am I?
Tell me!
[fearling laughs]
Oh, very well.
Lead on.
Show me what bleak future
my wickedness has wrought.
And, yes, nobody can see
or hear me, I know.
[sighs]
[magical jingling]
[fearlings laugh]
[Tom Jenkins] Ladies and gentlemen,
good morning to you
on this joyous Christmas Day.
We are gathered here as a group,
united by a common bond.
Namely, our feelings of gratitude
to Mr. Ebenezer Scrooge.
- [crowd cheer]
- I know that fellow.
Jenkins. Owes me 25... No, 50 pounds.
I must say he looks uncommonly happy
for a man so deep in debt.
In fact, most of this rabble
owes me money.
Shush. Shush.
While we are all deeply moved,
those of us who Mr. S was so kind
as to lend money to over the years
are particularly grateful
for what he has done for us today.
- [crowd cheers]
- What have I done?
Certainly not forgiven their debts.
As your predecessor said,
you are showing me
what will happen if I do not change.
I did not change, yet I am celebrated.
And rightly so.
These creatures have finally
come to their senses. That's it. Ha!
It would seem the ordeal
to which I have been subjected
has been a complete waste of my time.
And yours, my silent friend.
No matter. All's well that ends well,
as they say.
[woman] ♪ For he's a jolly good fellow ♪
That's right, Prudence.
They're cheering for me.
Yes.
♪ For I'm a jolly good fellow ♪
Ladies and gentlemen.
♪ On behalf of all the people
Who have gathered here today ♪
[cheering]
♪ I would merely like to mention
If I may ♪
[children giggle]
[Tom] ♪ That our unanimous attitude ♪
♪ Is one of lasting gratitude ♪
♪ For what our friend
Has done for us today ♪
♪ And therefore ♪
♪ I would simply like to say ♪
♪ Thank you very much
Thank you very much ♪
♪ That's the nicest thing
That anyone's ever done for me ♪
♪ I may sound double Dutch
But my delight is such ♪
♪ I feel as if
A losing war's been won for me ♪
♪ And if I had a flag
I'd hang me flag out ♪
♪ To add a sort of final victory touch ♪
♪ But since I've left my flag at home
I'll simply have to say ♪
♪ Thank you very, very, very much ♪
[crowd cheer]
[jolly music continues]
♪ Thank you very much
Thank you very much ♪
♪ That's the nicest thing
That anyone's ever done for me ♪
♪ It isn't every day
Good fortune comes your way ♪
♪ I never thought
The future would be fun for me ♪
♪ And if I had a bugle, I would blow it ♪
♪ To add a sort of
How's-your-father touch ♪
♪ But since I left me bugle at home
I'll simply have to say ♪
♪ Thank you very, very, very
Very, very, very, very, very, very much ♪
- [all] ♪ For he's a jolly good fellow ♪
- ♪ For who's a jolly good fellow? ♪
[all] ♪ He's a jolly good fellow ♪
♪ And so say all of us ♪
♪ [Tom] And if I had a drum
I'd have to bang it ♪
♪ To add a sort of rumpty-tumpty touch ♪
♪ But since I left my drum at home
I'll simply have to say ♪
♪ Thank you very, very, very ♪
- ♪ Much ♪
- [all] ♪ For he's a jolly good fellow ♪
Thank you very much!
- [Scrooge hums]
- [Prudence barks]
Ha, ha! Oh, yes, indeed.
This is far more agreeable
than what your predecessors had me endure.
So what's next, friend?
[fearling laughs]
[thunder crashes]
[shudders]
[Scrooge whimpers]
[lightning crackles]
[ominous music plays]
Tiny Tim.
- No.
- It's all right.
Cratchit, times are hard,
and my financial burdens are considerable.
- [Bob] My boy needs medicine.
- [Cratchit Sr.] It's Christmas Eve.
[Scrooge] Cratchit,
you do nothing but trouble me.
Should I add to them by paying
for the upkeep of your entire family?
I must go now, my little man.
[sad music plays]
I promised your mother
I'd help with Christmas dinner, but...
I'll come and see you again tomorrow.
Same time, all right?
[sobs] Oh, dear Tim.
- [Bob cries]
- Come on now, Father.
Till tomorrow then.
Sleep well, my love. Sweet dreams.
[sad music continues]
I...
I could have done more.
I could have done something.
Poor Tiny Tim.
Friend, you have shown me
a Christmas yet to come
that mixes great joy with greater sorrow.
Tell me, is this what will be,
or what may be?
If I were to change,
would all this still come to pass?
[man whistles "Thank You Very Much"]
[sad music continues]
[fearling cackles]
[man] Here.
[Tom strains]
- [Tom laughs]
- Gentlemen, please.
Sorry, Father. But you reap what you sow.
Is that not what your Good Book says?
I wouldn't hang about for any mourners.
Nobody's sorry to see this one go.
Nobody who doesn't walk
on all fours anyway.
Merry Christmas.
And thank you very much. [laughs]
[Tom sighs happily] Come on.
Earth to earth,
ashes to ashes, dust to dust.
[eerie whispering]
[menacing music plays]
[Scrooge gasps]
[Jacob] Scrooge...
[sinister music plays]
No.
[sinister music continues]
[ghost Scrooge moans]
Spare me.
Let me return.
I will not become this man
whose death is the cause
of such celebration.
[suspenseful music plays]
Why show me this if I am past all hope?
[suspenseful music continues]
Am I? Truly?
[thunder crashes]
If... If I am beyond salvation,
then so be it.
But, please, the boy need not die.
Not when I have it in my power
to help him.
I beg of you, spare me for this reason,
if nothing more.
[suspenseful music continues]
[bell tolls]
I swear to honor Christmas in my heart
and keep it there the whole year through.
I will learn from the past,
live only in the present,
and strive for a better future.
For all!
[whimpers]
[Scrooge strains]
Tell me I may yet strike the writing
from the boy's cross.
[strains] Tell me
I may yet break this chain! [grunts]
Please.
Please, tell me!
[fearlings squeal]
No!
[suspenseful music continues]
[Scrooge] No!
[Scrooge yells]
[suspenseful music continues]
[Jen] ♪ The wish that you wish
On Christmas Day... ♪
[Isabel] ♪ Goodbye... ♪
[Tim] ♪ On the beautiful day
That I dream... ♪
[Scrooge] No! No!
Please, no! No! Please, no!
[Scrooge screams]
[suspenseful music stops]
[Scrooge thuds]
[Scrooge] No! No!
Spare me! Spare me!
Please. Please!
[groans]
[moans]
[Prudence panting]
[Scrooge] Prudence?
Prudence!
[gasps] I'm in my bedroom.
Oh, it's Prudence.
[sighs happily]
[sighs]
Well, was I... Was I merely dreaming?
[Prudence sniffs and barks]
[Past laughs]
[Present laughs]
[gasps]
[indistinct chatter]
- You there!
- [man] Huh?
I-I say, what day is it, my fine fellow?
Um, Tuesday, I think.
Ha, no.
Is it Christmas Day?
Well, of course it is.
[Scrooge laughs]
♪ La, la, la! ♪
[grunts] Takes all kinds, I suppose.
It's Christmas, Prudence! [laughs]
- [Prudence barks]
- It's Christmas, and I'm alive! [laughs]
Wait, what time is it?
I'm glad Isabel found
the happiness she deserved.
Perhaps...
Perhaps it's not too late
for me to find my own.
[barks]
[cheerful exciting music plays]
- [sighs contentedly]
- I did. I swear. I said...
- Hello there.
- [girl] What?
[Scrooge laughs]
What is it?
We didn't do nothing, Mr. Scrooge.
No, not yet, you haven't. [laughs]
I have some errands for you to run.
I can make it worth your while.
[grunts]
Errands?
[tranquil music plays]
[Scrooge whistles]
Thank you, Prudence. There's a good girl.
[boy 1] Ah, ah, ah, ahh!
[Scrooge chuckles]
Mind how you go.
[girl] Mr. Scrooge, sir.
Almost done.
Magnificent.
What wonderful children you all are.
And, well, sorry to ask again,
but you're sure
you managed to get everything on the list?
Yes, sir.
The butchers and the bakers
thought I was having a laugh.
But then I gave 'em the checks.
They'll be here soon.
Splendid. And you did deliver
the invitations? All of them?
Of course.
No guarantee they'll come, though.
It is very short notice.
[laughs] Quite. Uh, you are
a clever young lady, aren't you?
As promised,
a gold sovereign for each of you.
Boys, since it's Christmas,
I ain't even gonna take my cut.
That's the spirit.
And you'll all stay for dinner, won't you?
Won't you?
- [all] Yay!
- [barking]
Ha! And help yourself to a gift.
[children] Yay!
- [boy 1] Come on.
- [boy 2] I get the biggest one.
Ready, Prudence?
[barks]
[jaunty music plays]
♪ I'll begin again ♪
♪ I will build my life ♪
♪ I will live to know ♪
♪ That I've fulfilled my life ♪
♪ I'll begin today ♪
♪ Throw away the past ♪
♪ And the future I build ♪
♪ Will be something ♪
♪ That will last ♪
[uplifting music plays]
- There we go. Comfortable enough, Ethel?
- Yes. Much obliged, Mr. Scrooge.
Good, good, good.
Oh, and please, call me Ebenezer.
- What's all this about then?
- Tom, your debt is canceled.
Merry Christmas, my friend.
Oh, and give my best
to your mother, won't you?
Thank you. Thank you very much.
[both] Oh, my giddy aunt!
Ladies, 1,000 pounds for your fund,
this and every Christmas to come.
[both] Oh, such generosity.
It's the doll from my mother's picture.
Uncle, I can't accept this.
You must.
It's a gift from an old fool who regrets
all the Christmases we never shared.
[Harry] Oh, Uncle.
[laughs] Thank you.
[uplifting music continues]
- "Business partners"?
- Yes, Bob. If you'll have me, that is.
Let's build a brighter future
for the Cratchits together.
- What do you say?
- [Bob] I say yes!
God bless you, Mr. Scrooge.
[uplifting music continues]
♪ I will start anew ♪
♪ I will make amends ♪
♪ And I'll make quite certain
That the story ends ♪
♪ On a note of hope, on a strong amen ♪
♪ And I'll thank the world
And remember when ♪
♪ I was able to ♪
♪ Begin ♪
♪ Again ♪
[Tim] God bless us, every one.
[upbeat music plays]
[Present] Uh! Here we go! Ha!
Come on!
♪ I love Christmas ♪
♪ I love Christmas
It's my favorite time of year ♪
♪ So enthralling ♪
♪ To see the snowflakes falling ♪
♪ To hear the children calling
Sweet words of Christmas cheer ♪
Let's go!
Come on, get up, ha!
♪ Church bells ringing ♪
♪ And people singing ♪
♪ Songs of Christmases gone by ♪
♪ Love and laughter
Reminding me forever after ♪
♪ Just why I love ♪
♪ Christmas ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Uh-huh, uh-huh, uh-huh ♪
One more time, one more time!
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
Hey, listen to me now.
♪ Jingle bells are jingling ♪
♪ Festive folks are mingling ♪
♪ Come on, come on ♪
Stop.
[laughter]
♪ I love Christmas ♪
♪ Cold and crispy Christmas ♪
♪ It's my favorite time of year ♪
♪ So enthralling ♪
♪ To see the snowflakes falling ♪
♪ To hear the children calling ♪
♪ Sweet words of Christmas cheer ♪
Ow!
- Whoo!
- Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
♪ Church bells ringing ♪
♪ And people singing ♪
♪ Songs of Christmases gone by ♪
♪ Love and laughter
Reminding me forever after ♪
♪ Just why I ♪
♪ Love ♪
♪ Christmas ♪
Hoo!
[upbeat music continues]
♪ Let me hear that saxophone! ♪
[saxophone plays upbeat music]
Merry Christmas!
[upbeat music ends]
[magical music plays]
[intriguing music plays]
[Bob] ♪ Christmas children
Peep into Christmas windows ♪
♪ See a world that's pretty as a dream ♪
♪ And Christmas presents shine
In the Christmas windows ♪
♪ Christmas boxes tied with pretty bows ♪
[Kathy] ♪ Wonder what's inside ♪
[Kathy and Tim] ♪ What delights
They hide ♪
[Bob] ♪ Until Christmas morning ♪
♪ No one knows ♪
♪ Christmas children
Hunger for Christmas morning ♪
♪ Christmas Day's a wonder to behold ♪
[Kathy and Tim]
♪ Young ones' dreams come true ♪
[Bob] ♪ Not-so-young ones' too ♪
♪ Christmas is for children
Young and old ♪
♪ So it goes that children everywhere ♪
♪ Will say a Christmas prayer ♪
♪ Till Santa brings ♪
♪ Their Christmas dreams ♪
[Kathy] ♪ Christmas children
Peep into Christmas windows ♪
♪ See a world as pretty as a dream ♪
[exciting magical music plays]
[exciting magical music crescendos]
[quiet magical music plays]
[mysterious music plays]
[mysterious music swells]
[music fades]